Guide to the Fred Eggan Papers 1870-1991
University of Chicago Library
- Series VI: North American Indian Files
  - Subseries 7: Plains
    - Caddo, Katsuwo Kasuga, "The Culture of Caddo Speaking People, " manuscript, 1936 (Box 70, Folder 24)
    - Caddo, Rudy C. Troike, "The Proto-Caddoan Kinship System, " manuscript, correspondence, 1965 (Box 70, Folder 25)
    - Cheyenne, Arapaho, notes, undated (Box 70, Folder 26)
    - Cheyenne, "Cheyenne #1, " field notebook, undated (Box 71, Folder 1-2)
    - Cheyenne, "Cheyenne #2, " field notebook, 1933 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Cheyenne, "Cheyenne #3, " "Arapaho #3, " field notebook, undated (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Cheyenne, "Cheyenne #4, " field notebook, undated (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Cheyenne, "The Cheyenne and Arapaho Kinship System, " manuscript, 1934 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Cheyenne, "Respect and Joking Relationships among the Cheyenne and Arapaho, " manuscript, undated (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Cheyenne, "The Social Organization of the Cheyenne, " manuscript, undated (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Cheyenne, Robert G. Armstrong, field notes, correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Cheyenne, Robert G. Armstrong, "The Acculturation of the Cheyenne and Arapaho Indians, " M.A. thesis, correspondence, 1942, 1965 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Cheyenne, Margot P. Liberty, "The Cheyenne Indians, " manuscript, correspondence, 1975 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Cheyenne, Alice L. Marriott, "The `Trades Guild' of the Southern Cheyenne Women, " manuscript, correspondence, 1940 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Cheyenne, University of Oklahoma Library, J. A. Shuck Collection, Western History Collection, "Kish Hawkins, Cheyenne, " photograph, 1984 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - Commanche, "The Social Organization of the Commanche, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Commanche, Daniel J. Gelo, reprint, 1987 (Box 71, Folder 15)
    - Commanche, E. Adamson Hoebel, "Commanche and 3H-kandika Shoshone Relationship Systems, " manuscript, correspondence, 1938 (Box 71, Folder 16)
    - Commanche, Stanton K. Tefft, "The Commanche System in Historical Perspective, " reprint, manuscript, notes, undated (Box 71, Folder 17)
    - Crow, notes, undated (Box 71, Folder 18)
    - Crow, Donald Collier, "Crow Field Notes, " manuscript, correspondence, 1939 (Box 71, Folder 19)
    - Crow, Margot P. Liberty, reprint, 1970 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Crow, Herbert Passin, "Kinship System of the Crow Indians, " student paper, 1938 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Crow, George Werner, "Social Organization of the Crow Indian Tribe, " student paper, 1947 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Dakota, notes, undated (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Dakota, Donald Collier, "Ogalala Field Notes, "1939 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Dakota, Raymond DeMallie, proposals, correspondence, 1971-1990 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Dakota, Stephen E. Feraca and James H. Howard, reprint, 1963 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Dakota, Ruth Landes, "Santee or Eastern Dakota, " field work synopsis, correspondence, 1953 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Dakota, Ernest L. Schusky, "A Dakota Kinship Group, " manuscript, correspondence, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Dakota, Fred L. Thomas, "Social Organization of the Teton Dakota, " student paper, undated (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Gros-Ventre, "The Social Organization of the Gros-Ventre, " manuscript, undated (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Hidatsa, notes, undated (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Hidatsa, Edward M. Bruner, "Pattern and Variation in Hidatsa Social Organization, " student paper, 1951 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Kansa, "Social Organization of the Kansa, " manuscript, notes, undated* (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Kiowa, notes, undated (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Kiowa, "The Social Organization of the Kiowa, " manuscripts, undated (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - Kiowa, Donald Collier, "Kiowa Social Integration, " student paper, manuscripts, 1937, 1938 (Box 72, Folder 17-18)
    - Kiowa, Jerrold E. Levy, "Organization of Research, " "Recent Changes in Kiowa Kinship Structure, " manuscripts, correspondence, 1958 (Box 72, Folder 19)
    - Kiowa, Truman Michaelson, reprint, 1923 (Box 72, Folder 20)
    - Kiowa, Arthur Sorensen, "A Comparison of Kiowa and Kiowa-Apache Social Organization with Particular Regard to Kinship Systems, and Ramifications in Other Plains Tribes, " student paper, 1952 (Box 72, Folder 21)
    - Kiowa-Apache, notes, undated (Box 72, Folder 22)
    - Mandan, Hidatsa, Arikara, notes, undated (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Mandan, Alfred W. Bowers, "A History of the Mandan and Hidatsa, " "A Research Proposal to the National Science Foundation, " outline, manuscript, ca.1960 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Mandan, B. Millen, "The Mandan, Hidatsa, and Arikara, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Omaha, notes, undated (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Omaha, "The Social Organization of the Omaha, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Omaha, Margot P. Liberty, "The Omaha Indians, " manuscript, reprints, 1974-1976 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Omaha, John Rinaldo, "A Comparison of the Omaha, Osage, and Kansa, " manuscript, undated (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Osage, "The Social Organization of the Osage, " manuscript, undated (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Oto, "The Social Organization of the Oto and the Missouri, " manuscripts, notes, undated (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Pawnee, "The Social Organization of the Pawnee, " manuscript, undated (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Parallels and Differences, " manuscript, 1936 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Piegan, Helen B. West, "The Starvation Winter of the Piegan Indians, 1883-1884, " leaflet, undated (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Ponca, "The Social Organization of the Ponca, " manuscript, undated (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Ponca, James H. Howard, "Social Organization, " manuscript, correspondence, 1957 (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - Quapaw, "The Social Organization of the Quapaw, " manuscript, undated (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - Wichita, "The Social Organization of the Wichita, " manuscripts, undated (Box 73, Folder 16)
    - Wichita, Karl Schmitt, field notes, correspondence, reprints, photograph, 1948 (Box 73, Folder 17)
    - Past and Present, " reprints, manuscript, 1951-1952 (Box 73, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 8: Great Basin
    - General, notes, undated (Box 73, Folder 19-20)
    - General, notes, undated (Box 74, Folder 1-2)
    - General, "Introduction, " Great Basin Anthropological Conference, The All-Conference Symposium on the Current States of Great Basin Anthropological Research, manuscript, correspondence, notes, 1964-1966 (Box 74, Folder 3-5)
    - General, "Introduction, " Donald Hardesty, correspondence, 1978 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - That Awesome Space, manuscript, correspondence, clipping, 1980 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - General, "Ph.D. Research Problem for Merton Oyler, " manuscript, 1940 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - General, L. S. Cressman, "The Northern Great Basin, " manuscript, 1964 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - General, Don D. and Catherine S. Fowler, reprints, correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - General, James Hooper, "The Social Systems of Steward's Basin-Plateau Sociopolitical Groups, " student paper, undated (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - General, Gordon Keller, "Social Organization of Some Basin-Plateau Groups, " student paper, 1948 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - General, Julian H. Steward, "Great Basin Area, " manuscript, reprint, ca. 1939, 1964 (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - A Pilot Great Basin Research Design, " "An Empirical Test for Steward's Model of Great Basin Settlement Patterns, " manuscripts, 1969, 1971 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Great Basin Settlements as Polythetic Sets, " manuscripts, 1973 (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - General, miscellaneous, reprints, 1955, 1975-1977 (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - Uto-Aztecan, notes, 1974 (Box 74, Folder 17)
    - Uto-Aztecan, Catherine S. Fowler, "Some Lexical Clues to Uto-Aztecan Prehistory, " manuscript, 1980 (Box 74, Folder 18)
    - Uto-Aztecan, James A. Goss, "Classification of the Uto-Aztecan Linguistic Stock, " "An Evaluation of Past Studies in Comparative Uto-Aztecan and a New Perspective for Future Work, " student papers, 1961, 1962 (Box 74, Folder 19)
    - Uto-Aztecan, Nicholas Hopkins, reprint, 1965 (Box 74, Folder 20)
    - Uto-Aztecan, Ronald W. Langacker, "The Reconstruction of Postpositional Expressions in Uto-Aztecan, " manuscript, 1974 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Uto-Aztecan, Wick R. Miller, "Classification of the Uto-Aztecan Languages Based on Lexical Evidence, " handout, 1980 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Uto-Aztecan, Kathleen Ray, correspondence, notes, 1976 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Bannock, notes, undated (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Paiute, notes, undated (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Paiute, W. B. Bowers, "Social Organization and Kinship System of the Owens Valley Paiute, " student paper, 1951 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Paiute, Katherine Pratt Ewing, "Myth as a Cultural Expression of Intra-Family Conflict among the Southern Paiute, M.A. thesis, 1973 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Paiute, Catherine S. Fowler and Joy Leland, "Some Northern Paiute Native Catagories, " manuscript, correspondence, 1967 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Paiute, M. Fuji, "The Social Organization of the Owens Valley Paiute, " manuscript, undated (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Paiute, Robert A. Manners, "Habitat, Technology, and Social Organization of the Southern Paiute, " clipping, 1959 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Shoshoni, notes, undated (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - The Shoshoni Case, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Shoshoni, "Shoshone Kinship Structures and Their Relevance to Levi-Strauss' `Elementary Structures, '" manuscript, abstract, notes, undated (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - Shoshoni, "Shoshone Kinship Structures and Their Significance for Anthropological Theory, " manuscript, notes, reprint, 1980 (Box 75, Folder 14)
    - Shoshoni, James A. Goss, "A Basin Plateau Shoshonean Ecological Model, " manuscript, 1972 (Box 75, Folder 15)
    - Shoshoni, D. B. Shimkin and Russell M. Reid, "Socio-cultural Persistence among Shoshoneans of the Carson River Basin (Nevada), " manuscript, undated (Box 75, Folder 16)
    - Settlement Patterns and Beyond, " manuscripts, correspondence, notes, 1971-1972 (Box 75, Folder 17-18)
    - Shoshoni, miscellaneous, reprints, 1945-1958 (Box 75, Folder 19)
    - Tübatulabal, M. Fuji, "Social Organization of the Tübatulabal, " manuscript, undated (Box 75, Folder 20)
    - Tübatulabal Kin Terms, " manuscript, undated (Box 75, Folder 21)
    - Ute, notes, undated (Box 75, Folder 22)
    - A Predictive Model, " manuscripts, "Ute Social Organization, " student paper, correspondence, 1961, 1974-1976 (Box 75, Folder 23)
    - Ute, Joyce Kayser, "Phantoms in the Pinyon, " photocopy, undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 9: Plateau
    - General, notes, undated (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - A Study of Intergroup Relations and Their Areal Framework, " dissertation abstract, 1954 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Flathead, W. A. Lessa, "Social Organization of the Flathead Indians, " student paper, 1940 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Klamath, notes, undated (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Kutenai, notes, undated (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Kutenai, Ray Birdwhistell, "Dissertation Proposal, " "Some Notes on Kutenai Social Organization, " manuscripts, 1942 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Kutenai, Unidentified, partial manuscript, undated (Box 76, Folder 8-9)
    - Salish, Frank Lynch, "Patterns in Consanguineal Kinship Terminology among Sixteen Salishan-Speaking Northwest Tribes, " student paper, correspondence, 1955 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Salish, Morris Swadesh, notes, correspondence, 1955 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Salish, Interior Salish, notes, undated (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 10: Northwest Coast
    - General, notes, undated (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - General, Gail Kelly, "Notes on Northwest Coast Political Organization, " manuscript, correspondence, 1956 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - General, Bruce MacLachlan, "An Appendix to the Social Organization of the Northwest Coast, " student paper, 1954 (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - General, University of Pennsylvania, The Museum Journal, 1913 (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - General, Unidentified, "Provisional Outline, " microcards, negatives, 1953 (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - Coastal Salish, notes, undated (Box 76, Folder 18)
    - Bella Coola, notes, undated (Box 76, Folder 19)
    - Haida, notes, undated (Box 76, Folder 20)
    - Haida, "Haida Clans," "Haida Towns," charts, undated (Box B)
    - Haida, Rosemary A. Allen, field notes, correspondence, reprints, 1952-1955 (Box 76, Folder 21-24)
    - Haida, Wilson Duff and Michael Kew, reprint, undated (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Haida, George P. Murdock, "Rank and Population among the Haida, " manuscript, correspondence, 1933 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Haida, Samuel L. Stanley, "Some Aspects of Haida Social Organization, " student paper, 1955 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Kwakiutl, notes, undated (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Kwakiutl, notes, Numayan organization, undated (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Kwakiutl, Anna M. Pikelis, "Social Organization of the Southern Kwakiutl Indians, " student paper, 1955 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Kwakiutl, miscellaneous, reprints, 1961, 1974 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Nanaimo, Sarah [Sally] Robinson, "The Family System and Social Change among the Nanaimo Indians of British Columbia, " manuscript, correspondence, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Nootka, notes, undated (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Nootka, Elizabeth A. Bruzewicz, "Nootka Social Organization, 1790-1890, " student paper, 1974 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Nootka, Alex Weingrod, "Kinship and Social Structure among the Vancouver Island Nootka, " student paper, undated (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Skagit, notes, undated (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Tlingit, notes, undated (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Tlingit, L. Hale, "Social Organization of North America, " student paper, undated (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Tlingit, Kalervo Oberg, "The Social Economy of the Tlingit Indians, " manuscript, undated (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - An Analysis of Tlingit Society, " manuscripts, correspondence, 1961, 1968 (Box 77, Folder 16-17)
    - Tlingit, Samuel L. Stanley, "Tlingit Project, " proposal abstract, correspondence, 1961 (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - Tlingit, Peter Stone, "A Developmental Cycle of a Tlingit Domestic Group in the 19th Century, " student paper, 1961 (Box 77, Folder 19)
    - Tlingit, miscellaneous, reprints, 1952, 1954 (Box 77, Folder 20)
    - Tsimshian, notes, n.d (Box 77, Folder 21)
    - Tsimshian, Marion Pugh, "A Sketch of the Kinship System of the Tsimshian, " student paper, 1955 (Box 77, Folder 22)
  - Subseries 11: California
    - General, notes, undated (Box 77, Folder 23)
    - General, Lowell J. Bean, "Power and Its Application in Native California, " "Social Organization, " manuscripts, correspondence, notes, 1974 (Box 77, Folder 24)
    - General, Lowell J. Bean and Harry Lawton, "Some Explanations for the Rise of Cultural Complexity in Native California with Comments on Proto-Agriculture and Agriculture, " manuscript, correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 77, Folder 25)
    - General, Francis B. Mahoney, "The Kinship Organization of the Athabaskan Speaking Tribes of Northwest California, " student paper, correspondence, 1948 (Box 77, Folder 26)
    - California Athabaskan, notes, undated (Box 77, Folder 27)
    - California Uto-Aztecan, notes, undated (Box 77, Folder 28)
    - Penutian, notes, undated (Box 77, Folder 29)
    - Yukian, notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Achomawi, notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Atsugewi, notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Chumash, notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Karok, notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Klamath, notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Lutuami, notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Modoc, notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Pomo, notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Pomo, Harold W. Scheffler, "Pomo Political Structure, " student paper, 1956 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Shasta, notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Yana, Yahi, notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Yokuts, notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 12: Southwest
    - Sub-subseries 1: General
      - Notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 14-15)
      - Maps, undated (Box A)
      - Review of unidentified book, partial manuscript, undated (Box 78, Folder 16)
      - "Comparative Social Organization, " manuscript, correspondence, 1981, 1983 (Box 78, Folder 17)
      - Preserving the Past in the Present for the Future, " manuscript, correspondence, ca.1984 (Box 78, Folder 18)
      - "Some Reflections on Fieldwork in the Southwest, " Southwestern Anthropological Association, lecture, manuscript, correspondence, 1979 (Box 78, Folder 19-20)
      - "The Southwest as a Region for Ethnological Research, " American Anthropological Association, manuscripts, correspondence, notes, 1988 (Box 78, Folder 21-22)
      - Seminar on the Southwest, syllabi, manuscripts, notes, 1953-1972 (Box 78, Folder 23-25)
      - Anthro 329, Problems in Southwestern Archaeology and Ethnology, syllabi, manuscripts, reprints, notes, undated (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - A Critical Review, " manuscript, notes, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 2)
      - Davis, Hilda A., "A Study of the Moral Ideology and Emotionalized Attitudes of Children in Three Tribes of Southwestern American Indians, " manuscript, 1953 (Box 79, Folder 3)
      - Fox, Warren and Robert, archaeology field notes, correspondence, clipping, ca.1938 (Box 79, Folder 4)
      - Hart, Janet Tietjens, "A Study of the Basket Maker and Pre-Pueblo, " manuscript, undated (Box 79, Folder 5)
      - Marlin, Joseph R., "An Overview of the Anthropological Writings of Josef Haekel, " student paper, 1955 (Box 79, Folder 6)
      - Metzger, Duane, "Preliminary Remarks Regarding Kinship System Change in the Southwest, " manuscript, 1955 (Box 79, Folder 7)
      - Ortiz, Alfonso, Indian Council Fire, Indian Achievement Award, manuscripts, 1982 (Box 79, Folder 8-9)
      - Studies in Cultural Continuity, seminar proposal, correspondence, 1978 (Box 79, Folder 10)
      - Santa Fe, New Mexico, map, undated (Box A)
      - Women Anthropologists and Students of the Native American Southwest, symposium, manuscripts, correspondence, notes, 1986 (Box 79, Folder 11-13)
      - Whiting, Alfred F., ethnobotany field notes, correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 79, Folder 14-15)
      - Southern Athabaskan, notes, undated (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - Yuman, notes, undated (Box 80, Folder 2)
      - Yuman, notes, file cards, n.d (Box 80, Folder 3)
      - Yuman, Eastern Yumans, notes, undated (Box 80, Folder 4)
      - Yuman, River Yumans, notes, undated (Box 80, Folder 5)
      - Yuman, Western Yumans, notes, undated (Box 80, Folder 6)
      - Yuman, George H. Fathauer, "The Social Organization and Kinship of the Yuman Tribes, " manuscript, correspondence, 1956 (Box 80, Folder 7)
      - Apache, notes, undated (Box 80, Folder 8)
      - Apache, Jicarilla, notes, undated (Box 80, Folder 9)
      - Apache, Western Apache, notes, undated (Box 80, Folder 10)
      - Apache, Fred Eggan, Fay-Cooper Cole, Harry Hoijer and Edward Spicer, Introduction to The Social Organization of the Western Apache, by Grenville Goodwin, manuscripts, 1941 (Box 80, Folder 11)
      - Apache, "The Social Organization of the Lipan, " manuscript, undated (Box 80, Folder 12)
      - Apache, "Summary of Chiricahua Apache, " manuscript, 1932 (Box 80, Folder 13)
      - Apache, Anne Harding, "The Kinship System of the Western Apache, " student paper, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 14)
      - Apache, Charles Kaut, "The `Clan System' as an Epiphenomenal Element of Western Apache Social Organization, " manuscript, correspondence, 1970 (Box 80, Folder 15)
      - Apache, M. E. Opler, "Some Points of Comparison and Contrast between the Treatment of Functional Disorders by Apache Shamans and Modern Psychiatric Practice, " manuscript, undated (Box 80, Folder 16)
      - Apache, Sol Tax, "The Apache Indians, " manuscript, undated (Box 80, Folder 17)
      - Apache, George Wallen, "Apache Murder of White Girl in 1930s, " transcript, 1964 (Box 80, Folder 18)
      - Cocopa, notes, undated (Box 80, Folder 19)
      - Diegueño, Rufus S. Herndon, Jr., "The Diegueño of San Diego County California, " student paper, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 20)
      - Havasupai, Yavapai, "Resumé of Havasupai and Southeastern Yavapai Cultures, " outline, undated (Box 80, Folder 21)
      - Havasupai, John F. Martin, notes, correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 80, Folder 22)
      - Kamia, notes, undated (Box 80, Folder 23)
      - Maricopa, notes, undated (Box 80, Folder 24)
      - Navaho, notes, undated (Box 80, Folder 25)
      - Navaho, foreword to Left-Handed, by Walter and Ruth Dyk, manuscript, notes, undated (Box 80, Folder 26)
      - Navaho, Malcolm Carr, "Preliminary Report on the Klageton Navaho, " "Preliminary Report on the Navaho Mountain Navaho, " manuscripts, correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 80, Folder 27)
      - Navaho, Ruth and Walter Dyk, "Son of Old Man Hat, " translation notes, correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 80, Folder 28)
      - Navaho, J. C. Harrington, "A Bibliography of the Navaho Indians, " manuscript, 1933 (Box 80, Folder 29)
      - Navaho, Harry Hoijer, "Navaho Phonemes, " manuscript, undated (Box 80, Folder 30)
      - Navaho, Philleo Nash, "A Memorandum in Support of a Research Project among the Navaho, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 80, Folder 31)
      - Navaho, Paiute, Stuart Struever, "Social Context in Two Far Western Societies, " student paper, 1960 (Box 80, Folder 32)
      - Pima, notes, file cards, undated (Box 80, Folder 33)
      - Pima, [Robert M.] Zingg, "Pima-Papago of the Southwest, " manuscript, undated (Box 80, Folder 34)
      - Seri, Edward W. Moser, Kin charts, undated (Box A)
      - Seri, Edward W. Moser, "Table of Terms--Seri, " chart, reprint, 1963 (Box 80, Folder 35)
      - Walapai, Flora Gregg Iliff, "The Beautiful Intoxication, " chapter eight of People of the Blue Water, manuscript, 1954 (Box 80, Folder 36)
      - Yaqui, Rosamond B. Spicer, "Living in Pascua, " manuscripts, correspondence, 1986 (Box 80, Folder 37)
      - Yaqui Ritual and Performance, correspondence, program, notes, 1981 (Box 81, Folder 1)
      - Yuma, notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous, clippings, pamphlets, newsletters, 1940-1990 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Foodways Project
      - Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 81, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, publicity, 1941-1942 (Box 81, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, S. D. Aberle, 1942 (Box 81, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, Harry Basehart, Oneida field notes, 1941-1942 (Box 81, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, John Collier, 1941-1944 (Box 81, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, Louisa J. Eskridge, 1941-1942 (Box 81, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, Robert L. Freedman, 1967-1969 (Box 81, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, Manuel Gamio, 1942 (Box 81, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, Antonio Goubaud Carrera, 1942-1943 (Box 81, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence, Solon T. Kimball, 1941-1942 (Box 81, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence, Margaret Mead, 1942, 1944 (Box 81, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence, Michel Pijoan, 1941-1943 (Box 81, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence, Robert Redfield, 1941-1943 (Box 81, Folder 16-17)
      - Correspondence, Emma Reh, 1941-1943 (Box 81, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence, J. T. Reid, 1940 (Box 82, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, Morris Siegel, 1941-1942 (Box 82, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, Donovan Senter, 1941 (Box 82, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, Leo W. Simmons, 1941 (Box 82, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, Mischa Titiev, diet charts, 1942 (Box 82, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, James B. Watson, 1942 (Box 82, Folder 6)
      - General, research notes, undated (Box 82, Folder 7)
      - General, research notes, diet charts, correspondence, 1942 (Box 82, Folder 8)